Hi, everybody. Welcome to English Digest. I'm Stephanie.
I am Tom.
Oh, I think this is my favorite unit, travel. Well, I like food, too.
But travel is so fun. We get to go to a brand new place we've never been before, and it's free.
I love that. You don't have to spend any money.
And today's destination is pretty beautiful.
I checked it online, and it's very close to Cannes, where they have the film festival.
Cannes, as some Americans pronounce it, or Nice, which is on the coastline of France, which is also very nice.
But Grasse is a UNESCO site as well.
I don't think we tell you that in our article, but it is.
They're trying to protect it because it is the heart of the perfume industry in the whole world.
This is where they go.
Indeed. When you think of fine perfume, of course, we think about France and the various brands that come from France and things like that.
If you travel overseas and you want to buy duty-free things, of course, lots of people like to buy French perfume.
I'm sure there's perfume from other countries as well, but the French one is the one that everybody wants to buy.
And, of course, you probably might not know about the history of perfume and where it comes from.
Why does it come from France?
Do French people really smell bad and they need some perfume to cover it up?
Oh, I'm not going to talk about that, but, yeah.
Could be, but I think still people like to have perfume all over the world, especially the ladies who want to smell nice and attract the boys, especially the ones with lots of money.
They can pick up a nice scent from the girl and get really interested in her.
And, of course, that's kind of what perfume is for.
But men wear something to smell nice and it's called cologne.
It's a different word.
C-O-L-G-N-E, cologne.
Yeah, different.
But, yeah, we're just talking about perfume today.
I'd love to talk about cologne because I don't use it myself.
Maybe I should learn a little bit more about that.
But, in any case, we're talking about this area of France that is famous for perfume and it's called Grasse.
It's the fragrance heart of France.
Let's listen to the first part right now.
Grasse, the fragrance heart of France.
Nestled in the hills of southern France, Grasse is famous as the world's perfume capital.
But did you know this charming town once smelled terrible?
In the 16th century, Grasse was known for its leather industry, not its sweet scents.
The air was filled with the smell of animal hides and chemicals used in tanneries.
To make their gloves more pleasant, local craftsmen began soaking them in flower-scented oils.
This clever idea not only improved the smell, but also started Grasse's journey into the world of perfume.
The real change came when a Grasse glove maker presented a pair of scented gloves to Catherine de' Medici, the Queen of France.
She loved them, she loved them, and perfumed gloves soon became a fashion trend among European royalty.
As high taxes made leather less profitable, skilled workers switched from making gloves to creating fragrances.
By the 17th century, Grasse had become a center of Europe's perfume trade.
Okay, guys, let's dive in.
Grasse is the name of the city, Grasse, France.
Grasse, France.
That's hard to say in English.
I guess you could say grass, but you'll sound a little uneducated.
Grasse.
Grasse of France.
And it's the fragrance heart of France.
Heart is often used to symbolize the core or the middle part of something.
So nestled in the hills of southern France, Grasse is famous as the world's perfume capital.
If you're nestled somewhere, it just means you're situated very comfortably or securely within something.
We often use it to talk about maybe a cabin that is nestled at the foot of the mountain.
So it's right there at the foot of the mountain, and it just feels like it's being protected by the sides of the mountain.
So here it's nestled in the hills of southern France, and as we said, it's the world's perfume capital.
Perfume can be pronounced two different ways.
Some people say perfume with the jong-in on the first syllable, perfume.
I tend to say perfume, and so does Tom.
So you can say either way.
They're both correct.
Indeed, and of course, we're not really going to talk about where this word comes from
because it's kind of complicated.
I think it's from French or Italian or something like that.
But basically, it just refers to Xiangshui, as you call it in Chinese.
But did you know this charming town once smelled terrible?
So this is a quaint, charming little town.
If something's charming, it's very attractive.
It has good manners.
You could describe a person as being very charming.
Of course, they have a very pleasant personality.
They're fun to talk to, and you feel captivated when you talk to them.
But this is a charming town, as are many towns in France, because they've got those old buildings
on those old streets, and they're really great to go to and walk around and take pictures of.
So, of course, this is a charming town.
But it actually smelled terrible at one time.
It actually stank, or stunk.
I don't know what the past tense of stink is, but I should just say it smelled terrible.
Oh, it did.
And for good reason.
Back in the 16th century, that's the 1500s, Grosse was known for its leather industry.
Now, nowadays, we think of leather and shoes and maybe purses and leather jackets.
But the leather industry, to produce some of the products that they made,
didn't, at the same time, produce really nice scents.
It was not known for its sweet scents.
Scents here is not, you know, change for money like a penny or a quarter or, you know, 50 NT.
Here, it just means something that smells good.
Usually, if you see this word S-E-N-T-S, it's a good smell.
If you see the word O-D-O-R, no.
Usually, we describe really nasty smells with the word odor.
So, the air was filled with the smell of animal hides and chemicals used in tanneries.
Let's talk about some of these words.
What's an animal hide, Tom?
Hide.
It means the animal doesn't want to be seen.
So, it's going someplace to hide.
No.
No, that's the verb form.
Here, hide is a noun.
It just refers to the skin of an animal.
Probably, it's the skin of a cow to make leather.
But I guess you can get skin from other animals like goats or whatever.
So, these are animal hides or animal skins, I guess you could say.
And also, we have the smell of chemicals that were used in tanneries.
A tannery is a factory, basically, that treats animal skins and makes them into leather and products that people can use, like clothes or upholstery for sofas or whatever.
That's what a tannery does.
If you ever see the word pelt, P-E-L-T, that's also an animal hide.
So, now you know three different words, skins, hides, and pelts.
And these tanneries, that's where, as Tom said, they would produce the animal skins or hides.
And they were usually near rivers because they needed a plentiful water supply, which I did not understand until I was preparing this lesson.
So, to make their gloves more pleasant, because, of course, they used gloves back in those days, and they still do, especially if you're a cowboy, you need your gloves.
They wanted to make the gloves smell better, because the chemicals and the things they'd have to put on the animal hides to make them, I guess, to cure them, to prepare them, smell terrible.
They wanted their gloves to be more pleasant.
So, the local craftsmen there in Grasse, they began something really clever.
They started soaking them, the gloves, in flower-scented oils.
Very smart.
So, if you're a craftsman, you're someone who is a skilled worker who usually makes things by hand.
Nowadays, we'll sometimes refer to these people as artisans.
Artisans, or craftsmen is a good word.
So, yeah, they would soak these gloves in flower oils.
If you soak something, you put it into something very wet.
So, maybe you have a stain that you got on your shirt, your brand-new shirt.
But when you were eating at lunch, you dropped some ketchup or whatever you're eating, and it made a stain on your shirt.
So, you're going to want to soak it before you wash it to get the stain out, and that's what we do.
We soak it.
So, you just put something into a liquid for a while.
Right.
You can do this with dishes, for example, if you eat something where the food kind of sticks to the bowl or the plate or whatever.
Or the pan, yeah.
It's probably difficult to wash it off right away, so you might want to soak it in water for a little while, maybe for a couple of hours or whatever.
And then it will be more easy or be easier to clean or to wash.
But here they would soak those gloves in flower-scented oils.
Okay, so they had some oils that had the smell or the aroma of those flowers that grow probably in that part of France there.
And, well, that would produce a really great smell, and it would kind of cover the foul smell of the animal hides and the chemicals and stuff like that.
And this clever idea not only improved the smell, but also started Grasse's journey into the world of perfume.
Okay, so, indeed, that's where it sort of started there.
I'm sure other countries in the past, ancient countries, had the concept of perfume.
But this is basically, or we're basically talking about the perfume industry in France.
Now, the real change came when a Grasse glove maker presented a pair of scented gloves to Catherine de' Medici, the Queen of France.
She was also started out as the Queen of Italy, just so you know.
Yeah, it does look like an Italian name.
Yeah.
The French say Catherine de' Medici.
They pronounce it differently.
But we in America say Medici, so we're going to, we take after the Italians, I guess you could say.
She loved these gloves.
Remember, they're scented, so they smell beautiful.
They don't smell like chemicals and animal hides.
They smell like flowers.
So, she loved them so much, and perfumed gloves soon became a fashion trend among European royalty.
She was pretty famous, of course, and so people like to copy famous people, whether they're celebrities today or maybe they're still royalty.
If you have royalty in your country, they like to copy what these people do.
So, a fashion trend started, a style that became popular for a time.
That's what a trend is.
So, that's how it really started getting more popularity is by Catherine de' Medici wearing them.
But, as government usually does, they raise taxes on everything.
So, high taxes made leather gloves and making these leather gloves less profitable.
They couldn't make a good profit.
So, these skilled workers that used to make the leather gloves switched from that industry to creating fragrances.
They just focused on the flower, flower-scented oils that they were making.
Right.
So, people probably bought their gloves somewhere else because these gloves had taxes on them, making them expensive.
Maybe they got to cheap imports from Spain or someplace like that or Morocco or wherever.
And so, the people there working said, well, we can't sell our gloves, but we still need to make a living.
So, they started to create fragrances.
Hey, let's take this oil with the flower smells in them and make it into perfume and try to sell it to people who like that sort of thing.
And by the 17th century or the 1600s, Grasse had become a center of Europe's perfume trade.
And so, that's where it all began.
And the rest is history.
We've got lots of wonderful kinds of perfume that come from France nowadays.
Some cheap, but some very expensive.
Oh, yeah.
You can spend a lot of money on perfume.
Right now, guys, we're going to take a few minutes and listen to our Chinese teacher, and then we'll be back.
Stay tuned.
听众朋友,大家好,我是安娜.
我們今天的旅遊單元要帶大家到法國的香水之都,Grasse.
這個法文我是這次不太會唸的。
好,那為什麼要到格拉斯Grasse呢?
其實這個城市啊,以前超級臭的,後來才變成香水之都。
可是啊,我們今天這個文章啊,不是單純看文章,我們是把它設計成篇章結構,而且是五選四哦。
學測啊,從今年開始啊,就是五選四。
所以五選四其實多了一個選項,這難度真的很高,你必須要去判斷說,那一句話是不是基本上都不可能會存在在這個文章當中,然後把它刪掉這樣子。
那另外一個重點就是說,現在它是篇章結構,我們要看到的是整體的一個面,也就是說,文章當中的整體的一個面的段落跟段落之間的這種連貫,文藝的連貫,才會是篇章結構真正的考點。
而不是那些小小的什麼,後面要加ING啦,還是什麼特殊劇型啊之類的。
好,所以這就導致我們在做答其實有一個技巧,也就是說,我們在瀏覽選項的時候可以先判斷一下這些選項,大概會出現在什麼樣文藝的段落當中。
例如A選項Grass,它的成功,香水製作的成功,就是因為它的自然環境啦。
那言下之一A選項,它會放在的段落應該是,那整個段落就在講說,Grass多適合種花啦,才能有精油啦,或者是香水之類的,有沒有。
好,我們有這個概念,我們會做一點筆記哦,或者是把那個natural environment特別把它抓出來。
好,那麼B選項就講到說,啊香水很貴啊,是因為人工貴啊,這些資源都很貴啊,那就是一種探討價格,以及這個這個原因的這個部分,那那個段落應該會提到香水的價格跟那麼貴的原因。
好,那麼第C的選項呢,特別先注意一下,它整個用的是was跟used,它是過去式囉。
所以之前的空氣的味道就是有那種動物皮革的味道,皮革場啊,用的化學的那些味道,所以C選項它會放在談到之前很臭的什麼樣的原因,因為皮革的怎麼樣的狀況,好的那個段落。
再來D選項呢,就講到哦,這個手作課程啊,還有visitors關鍵字,如果去那邊的話,遊客做一些什麼DIY啦,所以這一段應該會放在如果你到BRAS這個城市,大概可以做哪一些的參訪活動。
好,再來E選項呢,我們看到第一個,聚首的s,在這裡是because的意思哦。
還有一個重點,動詞也都用過去式了,我們看到made跟後面的switched,也就是因為高稅的關係,就使得這個大家不做皮革了,我做香水,是談到一個過去從做皮革改做香水的一個改變。
其實我們在看選項的時候,大概就可以預測文章,大概又介紹這個BRAS的什麼東西啦。
好,當然我們就趕快回到我們的第一段啦。
第一段真正的主旨句啊,是出現在第二句的地方。
這個第二句他就用了did you know,但是你之前知不知道它這個城市啊,其實蠻臭的。
好,我們看到這個臭的這個關鍵,大概就會想到哦,它應該會跟什麼之前的氣味不好啦,這樣子的一個描述有關對不對。
所以我們來到了第一題的時候,前文這一句話我們講到十六世紀啊,它是在做皮革的,並不是做香水的。
第一題之後,我們看到的是為了讓他們的手套聞起來更香一點,才把它浸在所謂的這個有花香的這種精油當中。
好,所以第一個我們蠻確定的這個第一題應該就是在選C這個選項。
也就是說空氣之前的味道就是因為這些皮革動物的味道,還有化學藥劑。
所以啊,後來才會變成會有這個香味出現。
好,那麼接著我們就來看到了第二段啊。
第二段就講到改變為什麼?
因為我們看到的篇章,尤其是篇章結構這種文章,它一定會特別設計的讓你的第一段的第一句這個主題句非常明顯。
我們看到第二段的第一句,the real change,真正的改變。
改變這個字,你有沒有想到我們剛剛在E選項有一個switched,轉而去做香水呢?
所以第二題根據上下文的文意,我們選E是比較通順的。
我們選擇了解決定。
Welcome back, everybody.
We're going to continue talking about Grasse and the beginnings of perfume there in Grasse.
Remember, they were a place that produced leather.
But, of course, when they produced leather in tanneries, the leather smelled really bad.
The animal hides themselves and the chemicals really stank.
They smelled terribly in those tanneries.
And so, of course, the gloves were stinky as well.
So they would soak them in these flower-scented oils.
And thus, they started to produce perfume at the same time as the leather.
Of course, later on, the government started to tax leather.
And so those gloves got to be too expensive.
So nobody wanted to buy them or at least not buy gloves in France itself.
So they switched their industry around and started to produce perfume there.
And as I said, the rest is history.
And now you can go to Paris or duty-free shops all over the world and buy perfume.
You know, either fairly inexpensive or very expensive, whatever you want.
Okay, so let's move on now and talk some more about Grasse in the second part of our lesson.
Here we go.
Grasse's success is also due to its natural environment.
The mild Mediterranean climate, fertile soil, and abundant rainfall create ideal conditions for growing flowers, like roses, jasmine, and lavender, which are key ingredients in perfume.
Even today, fields of colorful bloom surround the town, and farmers continue to harvest flowers for their precious oils.
Visiting Grasse is like stepping into a fragrant dream.
You can tour historic perfume factories where guides explain how flowers are turned into luxurious scents.
The International Perfume Museum tells the history of perfume through antique bottles and interactive exhibits.
For a hands-on experience, visitors can join DIY perfume workshops and create their own unique scents under expert guidance.
Grasse's influence extends far beyond France.
Many famous perfumes were born here, and its perfumers remain highly respected today.
It's a place where history, nature, and creativity come together, and where every scent tells a story.
Okay, guys, welcome back.
We're going to be moving on to part two.
We learned that once they started raising taxes on leather products and leather goods, those skilled craftsmen decided,
well, I need to make a good living, so what else can I do in this area?
And they went into the perfume-making business.
And at that point, in the 17th century, Grasse became the center of Europe's perfume trade.
If you wanted to, if you were a merchant, somebody in that trade, you would go to Grasse and buy your big supply,
and you'd trade with them, something else, and then you would leave and go back to your country or city
and sell that perfume for a nice profit.
Well, Grasse's success is also due to where it's located and its natural environment.
They're really close to the Mediterranean, and so the climate there is very mild.
You can grow a lot of wonderful things there.
They also have very fertile soil.
If the soil is fertile, it just means you can grow a lot of plants and flowers there.
They grow without too much trouble.
You don't have to keep, you know, watching them to see if they'll produce.
It's just an easy place to grow things.
They also have an abundant rainfall there, so it creates the ideal conditions for growing flowers that smell good.
Here are the flowers that are really, really fragrant.
They're roses, jasmine.
I have a jasmine plant on my balcony that I love, and that smell will come into my apartment.
I just think, oh, it's heaven.
Lavender also grows very well here in Taiwan.
There's a wonderful place that's pretty close to us, a couple hours away, that you can go and see the lavender fields.
These are flowers that are used as key ingredients in perfume.
What's an ingredient, Tom?
Something that is included as a larger whole, so you have all these ingredients mixed together to create something bigger.
If I want to talk about, say, boba tea or pearl milk tea, of course, the ingredients would be the tapioca balls.
It would be black tea and milk and sugar and things like that.
Those are the ingredients for that particular drink.
And, yes, indeed, if you want to make perfume, you need to have these different kinds of ingredients.
And I guess you can mix these in different ratios along with other kinds of spices and things like that to get different kinds of smells because, yeah, perfume comes in all sorts of different varieties.
And, of course, it's always fun to try to find the one that you like the best and is most suitable for you and your body type or whatever.
So, yes, indeed, these are some examples of the ingredients, roses, jasmine, and lavender.
And even today, fields of colorful blooms or flowers surround the town and farmers continue to harvest flowers for their precious oils.
So, if you go to this town, you'll probably be very surprised to see lots of colorful flowers growing around the town.
These fields surround the town.
It's all around the town, maybe more in certain parts of the year and less in others.
But you could, of course, do some research and figure out the best time to go to see those flowers and get some pictures and stuff like that.
And, of course, the farmers use those flowers to produce those oils and to produce perfume.
I kind of skipped over one of the vocabulary words here, mild.
We use it to talk about things that aren't very hot or cold.
We'll also use it to talk about spicy food.
Sometimes on a menu, it will say mild or very spicy.
So, I like mild a little bit better.
But just moderate, kind of gentle.
If you're on a coastline, it's usually not very cold or not very hot.
But that doesn't apply to some countries, of course.
Some countries, it doesn't matter.
It's where they're based.
Are they near the equator or not?
So, this is a place that's kind of mild.
It's got really pretty good weather, I must say.
It's not a bad place to go in the winter.
It can get chilly.
Don't think it doesn't get a little bit chilly.
But fertile, we talked about rainfall.
They'll often use rainfall just to talk about the amount of rain in a place.
Or sometimes you'll see the word precipitation.
Indeed.
Okay.
So, of course, they've got ideal conditions there.
They do.
To grow those flowers.
That happens all over the world.
There are certain parts of the world that are ideal for growing certain things.
And thus, certain areas are famous for a special kind of product.
Like here in Taiwan, of course, the custard apple is very famous from Taidong because I guess they have ideal growing conditions for that down there.
But moving on to the next paragraph here, it says, visiting grass is like stepping into a fragrant dream.
Yeah.
So, if something's fragrant, it sounds, excuse me, it smells really nice.
Okay.
And a related word is fragrance.
And, of course, if you watch perfume commercials, they often say, we'd like to introduce a new exciting fragrance for you.
And, of course, it's probably going to cost you lots of money and stuff like that and come in a really nice glass bottle or something like that with a special shape.
So, yeah, if you go there, ooh, you're like walking into a dream that smells really nice.
If you go at the right time of the year, it would be amazing because they have fields of flowers.
You can tour historic perfume factories where they tell you the history of the perfume industry and they explain how flowers are turned into luxurious scents.
Luxurious is a word that when I see it, I think, cha-ching, which just means a sound effect for money.
It can be very comfortable, but it's usually elegant and expensive.
They also have the International Perfume Museum in that area, and it tells the history of perfume through, this is how they tell you, they have lots of antique bottles there and interactive exhibits.
If it's an antique, it's got to be over 100 years old.
That's the unofficial definition of an antique anything.
That's what my mom told me.
Yeah, my mom told me that, too.
I got that from my mom.
Interactive exhibits means you can put your hands on something, and depending on what buttons you push or what you're doing, you get something different in return.
An exhibit is usually a public showing of something.
You can go to a science exhibit.
An art gallery has lots of different exhibits or exhibitions, but here an exhibit is fun.
If it's interactive, it's a hands-on kind of thing.
They also have a DIY perfume workshop, and they'll let you actually decide what your own special perfume bottle is going to have inside it.
That would be fun.
I would totally do this.
I guess you'd have to go to a glassmaker to design your own bottle for it.
Of course, that's one of the attractions to buying perfume is the actual bottle and its design.
And here in the final paragraph, it says,
Grasse's influence extends far beyond France.
Okay, so, of course, it's very influential in France itself, but, of course, it's spread over to other countries.
Many famous perfumes were born here, and its perfumers remain highly respected today.
So, of course, lots of people around the world know about this region, and they know about their products.
So, of course, these people are very famous.
It's a place where history, nature, and creativity come together and where every scent tells a story.
If you've ever seen a movie about perfume, you'll hear them call these perfumers, le nez.
Le nez means the nose in French.
Okay.
And even today, if you're in the perfume industry, those who make new perfumes come up with new scents and fragrances.
They're called le nez, the nose.
Indeed, and I'm not really into perfume myself, but I really think those bottles are cool.
Yeah.
The way they have the glass shapes and things like that, I think they're quite cool.
I think a lot of people actually collect those little bottles.
Oh, interesting.
Not necessarily for the perfume inside, but for the actual bottles themselves.
And that brings us to the end of our explanation for today.
Let's hear one more time from our Chinese teacher.
接著就来到了第三段咯。
第三段的第三题是第三段的主题句耶。
所以其实主题句的话,它必须要文词比较模糊,
然后会包含接下来谈到比较具体的东西。
哪些东西呢?
第三段,我们看到第二句。
The mild military climate.
这个很温和的这种地中海型的气候。
Fertile soil,土壤很好。
Abundant rainfall,然后呢,雨水又很丰富。
诶,这个不就是在谈一个自然环境吗?
所以第三题,我们应该是选A。
啊,原来它的成功是因为它自然环境那么好。
我们接下来再喵喵,哦,所以它种花啦。
哦,种花就可以种得很好啦,这样子。
诶,这边是很通顺哦。
哦,所以第三题应该是选A,没有错。
接着呢,我们就来看到最后面的第四段。
一开始的也同样主题句,visiting grass。
如果我们去拜访的时候啊,啊,要做一些什么事情。
接下来就只剩下两个嘛。
一个就是B选项,还有一个D选项。
B选项我们刚刚说过是在探讨,
诶,香水为什么会这么贵啊,它的原因。
那么D选项呢,则是游客可以有参加哪些活动呢?
所以在第四段,第四题前面一句话,
博物馆呢,就可以去参观,
然后游客呢,可以做哪些东西,都没有提到价格。
所以第四题应该选第一选项是最同顺的。
希望今天借由这篇文章对篇章解题技巧有些概念哦。
我是Anna,我们下次见。
That's all the time we have, guys.
Thanks for joining us.
And the next time you go to the department store,
take a look and see what new perfumes are out on the market
and see if you can guess the flowers,
what they've put inside that,
the ingredients.
Maybe you're lanae,
or maybe you're meant to be in the perfume industry as the nose as well.
That's all we have today.
Join us again for English Digest.
I'm Stephanie.
I'm Tom.
Goodbye.
Bye.