Hi, everybody. Welcome to English Digest. I'm Tom.
I'm Stephanie.
It's our literature unit for our magazine. And literature, of course, talks about books.
And books can be in different forms. It can be poetry. It could be nonfiction.
But we're talking about a novel here. It's called Forget Me Not.
And that brings Tourette syndrome to light. That's kind of interesting because it's talking
about Tourette syndrome, which is when people have involuntary actions in their bodies. They
might blink their eyes or move their arms a certain way and they can't control it.
And in the extreme cases of Tourette's, they actually scream obscenities and things like
that. But those are less common than the normal ones of just simple body movements and things
like that. And this book is kind of about that. It's the story of someone's journey from being
kind of bullied because of that to finding understanding later on.
One of my favorite nephews has Tourette's. And you can call it Tourette's with an apostrophe
S or Tourette syndrome. We just say Tourette's. It's faster. And we didn't know at first, right?
But it's been interesting to see his journey. He is so adorable and loving and kind that he's
a best friend to everybody. Everyone loves him. So we never had to go through bullying.
But it is better now that we know why he's doing these funny moves with his body.
Indeed. So it can manifest itself in different ways. But we're going to talk about the main
character, Calliope Snow or Callie for short. So let's find out what her story is all about
in this novel. Forget Me Not. Let's listen to the first part of today's lesson and we'll come
right back. Forget Me Not brings Tourette syndrome to light. Calliope Snow, known as Callie, has never
stayed anywhere long enough to feel rooted. After her father dies in a car accident, her mother becomes
unstable and dependent on boyfriends. Every breakup means another move. Now on her 10th relocation,
Callie desperately prays for something different. Friends and a place that finally feels like home.
However, Callie carries a secret that refuses to stay hidden. She has Tourette syndrome, a neurological
condition triggering uncontrollable sounds and movements. Both her mother and physician urge
her to hide it. On her first day, she wears baggy clothes and hopes classmates notice her outfits,
not her tics. They notice anyway, and stares, whispers, and bullying follow her everywhere.
Okay, guys, let's dive in. Forget Me Not. For those of you out there that love flowers and plants like
I do, you may have heard of the flower Forget Me Not. They're called Forget Me Nots because they're
plural, but they're quite beautiful. And this is what our author, Ellie Terry, that's her name,
she decided to name her first novel. This is her debut novel. If it's a debut, it means it's the first time
it's been released to the public. It's an introduction of something, your debut novel,
your debut recital, your debut album. All of these things are the first time you've been releasing
whatever you have to the public. And Forget Me Not is a really kind of a wonderful title, I think.
She's an American poet and novelist. And she also lives with Tourette syndrome. And she's used that,
which most authors use their own lives to write about things, even if it's fictional. They use what
they know to write about. And that's what she's done. I think there's somebody on YouTube or on TV
somewhere that's got a regular show about this girl that has it. I think her name is Balin Dupree
or something like that. Maybe you've heard of her before. It's kind of like a reality TV show.
And it shows how she deals with Tourette's and other issues she has in her life.
Oh, yes, I have heard of her.
You have. Okay. Lots of people probably have. And that's good because she's bringing awareness to
this problem. And hopefully people will understand it. And they will stop bullying people who have
this problem. And that's kind of what this book is doing as well. We're talking about Calliope
Snow. That's the main character. She's known as Callie. And she has never stayed anywhere long
enough to feel rooted. If you feel rooted, you feel like you belong someplace. And if you're an army
child or something, if your parents are moving around all the time, like if you're in the army,
the U.S. military, they go to different bases all over the world and all over the United States. So
they probably never feel rooted. They're always moving every two or three years. So they never
really feel like they belong anywhere.
Yeah, it would be hard. We call those people military brats. They'll describe themselves as
being military brats. And they do move, you know, every couple of years. So you have to be really good
at making friends because you're going to new schools constantly. I've had a couple of friends who have
been military brats. And they're very flexible. And they're very good at making new friends. They're
confident. It can affect kids different ways, right? So it can be really good for you. But it can also hurt
those who are extremely shy or who are struggling with something unusual. And Tourette syndrome is
unusual. If you don't have any contact with somebody with Tourette's, you wouldn't know what's going on.
So people, especially kids, they can be cruel and kind of mean sometimes instead of trying to figure out,
how they can be better friends to someone or make sure someone feels comfortable, they'll start making
fun of someone instead. So she's never stayed long enough to feel rooted. After her father dies in a
car accident, her mother becomes unstable. So her mom isn't very steady. She becomes very dependent on
boyfriends. She, you know, has a boyfriend for a while, gets rid of him, gets a new one. He lasts for a
couple of months. She dumps him or he dumps her and she gets another boyfriend. If you're dependent on
somebody, you need them to get along in life. And you don't ever want to be so dependent on something
or someone that you can't be happy when they're gone. That can be really important. So she's, I would say
her mother's kind of needy. Needy is a good word for her mother. She's kind of needy and needs those
boyfriends. But meanwhile, her daughter needs her to step up and be a good parent. And her mother's
more concerned about her own personal life. Right. Her mother may have been just a housewife or something
like that. So when the father died, the mother had to take responsibility for the family finances and
stuff like that. Maybe didn't have a lot of job responsibility or job experience, I should say.
So she depended on boyfriends. She was dependent on boyfriends. And every breakup means another move.
So yeah, if she breaks up with a boyfriend, that's two words there. Break up as the verb phrase.
If she breaks up with somebody, then they have to move to another town or another state or something
like that. And then breakup as one word makes it a noun. So after every breakup, she has to move to a new
town. Now her mother is on her 10th relocation, which means Callie's on her 10th move or relocation as
well. A relocation is when you relocate or you move to a new place to live. It could be across town,
but it's still in a new school, which makes it difficult, especially when you get into those
teenage years. Oh, it's tough then because you feel extra sensitive and insecure. It's just part of
life. We all go through it. Even those who pretend they're confident as teens, everyone feels insecure,
guys. You're not the only one. So Callie desperately prays for something different. She wants to have
friends in a place that finally feels like home. So she's praying to God for that, hoping that something
good will happen in her life. Now, however, it says in the next paragraph, Callie carries a secret that
refuses to stay hidden. It's one of those secrets that's hard to hide. If it's Tourette's, it's very
visible. You either are doing something funny with your body, your body's moving without you
consciously moving it yourself, or maybe you're making noises or sounds. Sometimes people will go
you know, little ticks with their mouths. Tourette's can be different things. The people who have Tourette's
cannot control those things. Although with therapy, they have systems that can help them overcome some
of those tics. Right. And those are tics. Those are things that, well, that's the word we use to
describe those emotions that a person with Tourette's has if they suddenly jerk their body or if they yell
out really loud or something and they can't control it. Those are called tics. So yes, indeed, this is her
next location. And she wants to feel like she's at home, but she carries a secret again that's hidden.
She has Tourette syndrome. What is that? It's a neurological condition triggering sounds and movements or tics,
as we call them, tic. To trigger just means to cause something to happen. Like on a gun, for example, if you pull the trigger, then it will shoot a bullet through the air and hit the target. Okay. So yeah, trigger. It's triggered by various things. And of course, they can't control this because it's a neurological condition. It has to do with the brain and the nerves and things like that.
Uncontrollable could also be substituted with involuntary. Voluntary means you want to
want to do something. Involuntary means you don't want to do something. And yeah, trigger just means it's causing something to start. Maybe you've said something really mean to your boyfriend and he loses his temper and he gets mad. Well, you've triggered that emotional response in him.
You started it by saying something cruel or mean. Both her mother and physician give her kind of weird advice, I think.
They say, hey, you should hide the fact that you have Tourette's syndrome. But I think if you're more open about what you're struggling with, people will have more compassion on what you're going through.
Maybe people who don't know you're struggling with it think you're doing it on purpose. That's worse.
So her physician. Physician is another word for doctor. They're both correct. I think physician's a little bit more gaoji, but not really.
Doctor, physician. They're telling her, hey, Callie, you should hide the fact that you have it.
Right. And of course, that's easier said than done because Tourette's is kind of uncontrollable.
It's very visible. But I think this is probably a time where people didn't really understand it as well as they do now.
So, again, they urge her to hide it. If you hide it, you know, you can control it, you know, so you'll be OK.
Just don't let people see it. So on her first day of school, she wears baggy clothes and hopes classmates notice her outfits, not her ticks.
We did just mention the word tick there as movements or whatever. And baggy clothes are loose clothes that are probably too big for you.
That can be rather popular in some communities by wearing baggy shirts or baggy pants or something like that.
And of course, a baseball cap and lots of chains around your neck and stuff like that.
That can be very fashionable to wear loose fitting clothes or baggy clothes that look like bags on your body.
Yeah, if you see, if you're buying clothes and you say to the sales clerk, hey, it looks a little baggy.
Do you have a smaller size? Or do you have a size that would fit me better?
Baggy is just really loose. And some people really like those clothes, as Tom said.
They can be stylish depending on the trends.
Right now, guys, we are going to take a quick break.
Listen to our Chinese teacher for a bit and then we'll be back.
Hello everyone,我是Patrick老师.
今天讲解的是 Forget Me Not Brings Tourette's Syndrome to Light.
这个单元介绍的是 Forget Me Not月亮都是一样的这本书.
大家的成长过程当中有没有遇过转学生?
还是各位自己本身就是转学生呢?
如果你曾经是转学生,或许比较能体会书中主角不断重新适应环境的苦,
有难言之隐的话更能体会吧。
好,我们一起来看学习重点。
来,请看第一段。
最后面这个Rooted,这是一个过去分词。
第一段开头先交代人物,小说的主角呢是女孩子,名字叫Kelly.
那第一句很特别哦。
这里呢,作者用简单两三个字传达出主角的心理状态。
Never feels rooted.
那也就是我们的主角呢,他怎么样?
他从来没有觉得呢在这里有连结,有根。
好,这里是一种比喻的说法。
那rooted就好像说树哦,把根深深地扎在土里。
那如果一个人觉得rooted就是跟这个地方有连结。
那从后面三个句子,我们就可以看得出来为什么Kelly觉得自己没有根。
好,我们继续往后看。
那第二句好第三句交代了Kelly的家庭背景。
爸爸车祸过世,妈妈情绪不稳,不断换男朋友,一个换过一个,那他们呢也要跟着搬家。
我们再来看到第四个句子,好,这里讲到搬家搬到第十次的时候,Kelly希望能够交到朋友,能够有家的感觉。
请同学注意的这个relocation。
好,动词呢是relocate。
搬迁,迁移。
像我们都知道说像印尼哦,其实他们呢的首都啊,有这个海平,等于是海平面上升的问题啊,那受到气候边迁的影响。
所以印尼呢是计划要迁都的,我们就可以用relocate来造个句子。
Indonesia is planning to relocate its capital from Jakarta to Nusantara。
好,那这地方在哪里呢?
是在印尼的东加里曼丹。
好,那我们再来往后看,看到呢第二段的第一个句子。
Kelly carries a secret that refuses to stay hidden.
好,这边所讲的呢就是藏不住的秘密哦。
这边这个动词refuses,用得很好。
那一般而言呢,秘密是抽象概念,它本身没有人的意志。
作者呢说秘密拒绝躲藏,其实呢会让我们觉得用得很生动,就像小孩子调皮啊,不受控。
让我们可以感受到主角这个Kelly很无奈,他也没办法控制。
再来我们看到第二句就清楚点出主角呢,他有什么样的问题呢?
他有Tourette syndrome。
好,那这是什么样子的困扰?
A neurological condition。
这是属于呢,就等于是呢,他在神经系统方面有一些问题。
再来我们看到第四个句子,这里就讲到哦,主角Kelly他去上学的时候呢,就在第一天发生了什么状况?
他刻意啊,希望啊,就是同学注意到是他的衣服哦。
不要注意到他的Nod和Ticks。
Ticks这里主要指的呢,就是一种很突然,快速反复,而且呢,就是奇怪的肌肉动作或者发出声音。
好,那第五个句子这边就讲到说同学还是注意到啦,那同学呢,就切切私语,而且等于是他还遇到了一些霸凌的状况。
We're going to take a quick break.
Stay tuned, we'll be right back.
Welcome back, guys.
It's our first day of our literature unit, which is a two-day unit.
We're talking about the new book, Forget Me Not, written by author Ellie Terry.
I think her name is.
We're going to talk about her in day two.
She wrote the book, which also has a lot about her own struggles with Tourette's syndrome.
Authors often use what they know about to write novels, even though they're fictional, they still contain, you know, some truths in there.
Our main character's name is Calliope Snow.
That's an unusual name.
Calliope, you don't see very often.
We will have a lot of Callies around.
I know two Callies, actually, in the States.
And their full name isn't Calliope, it's just Callie.
But Calliope is a name that means beautiful voice.
And it was also a muse of epic poetry in Greek mythology.
So I think that's where this name actually comes from.
Our author writes poetry as well as novels.
So I think she picked that name on purpose.
So when we left you, we learned a little bit about the main character, Callie.
She is often uprooted.
Her father died in a car accident and her mother became kind of dependent on boyfriends.
And when she'd break up with a boyfriend, she would have to move.
So Calliope is just taken from one place to another.
She's on her 10th relocation.
And she just wants to stay put and feel some roots and have some friends that she can rely on.
Now, she has a secret that refuses, it says, to stay hidden.
And that says she has Tourette's.
And it's a neurological condition, something that happens in her brain that triggers these involuntary sounds and movements.
Some people who have Tourette's only move involuntarily.
Some have sounds that come out of their mouths.
Some yell words.
And some people think that they're doing it intentionally and they're not.
It's uncontrollable.
It's not on purpose.
Both her mother and her doctor say, oh, you should hide the fact that you have this.
So she follows their advice, which I think is terrible advice.
And she wears baggy clothes to school, hoping her classmates won't notice her tics, but they'll focus in on her outfits, which are kind of baggy.
But they notice anyway.
And they start staring and whispering and bullying her.
So she's had a difficult time as she's had to relocate so much.
Okay, but this story kind of has a happy ending.
So we're going to find out what happens next in the next part of our lesson.
So let's listen and we'll be right back to discuss it.
The only exception is Jin Sung, her Chinese-American neighbor and the school's prominent student body president.
Drawn to Callie from the day she moves in, Jin Sung dreads losing his reputation.
He talks with her after school, but avoids her in public.
Still, his sincerity builds trust and a genuine friendship blossoms.
When his friends mock Callie again, Jin Sung erupts, punches them, and ends up being suspended.
Then, Callie's world shifts without warning.
Her mother impulsively marries a new boyfriend and announces a move to Las Vegas, Nevada, U.S.
Before she departs, Callie shares one last walk with Jin Sung, and he kisses her farewell.
On the drive, Callie confronts her mother about the pain of constant moving and concealing her condition.
Her mother apologizes, and they begin communicating more openly.
At her new school, Callie introduces herself honestly and discloses her Tourette syndrome.
Surprisingly, her classmates respond with warmth and acceptance.
Callie and Jin Sung stay in touch, and she's already planning a summer visit.
Welcome back, everybody.
Let's talk about the second part of our lesson for today.
Remember, where we left off, Callie had started a new school.
She'd started going to a new school, but her doctor and her mother told her,
well, you should hide your tics.
You know, you shouldn't let other people notice that.
So, of course, she wore clothes, baggy clothes, but that didn't work.
The people noticed.
They stared at her.
They whispered, and they started to bully her.
But the only exception is Jin Sung, her Chinese-American neighbor and the school's prominent student body president.
So, the exception here, the person who did not whisper behind her back and who did not stare at her and who did not bully her,
well, that was Jin Sung.
And he's a Chinese-American person, which means he's an American, but he has a Chinese ancestry.
Maybe his parents or grandparents immigrated to the United States at a certain time.
And he's also, well, he's their neighbor.
He lives next to them.
And he also happens to be a prominent student or the prominent student body president,
which means that's the student government there.
Student government is the student body.
He's the president of the school government, the student government.
And he's prominent there, which means he sticks out, he's important, and everybody notices him, and they respect him.
Yeah, we elect our student body presidents once a year.
They have campaigns at the beginning of the year, and they promise all these things,
like they're going to get you extra snack food machines installed, and they're going to give you extra breaks,
and they're going to have a better prom, all of these things.
It's kind of fun.
But he's popular among his classmates.
You have to be popular to be elected to be student body president.
Prominent means you're easily noticed or important.
I think here it means a little of both.
Everyone knows who he is.
I call him Jin Song because it's more Chinese to me.
Tom calls him Jin Song.
You can call him whatever you want.
He's drawn to Callie.
I think he's attracted to her.
I think he is interested in her as a girl, as a person.
And from the day she moves in, he dreads losing his reputation by hanging out too much with her, I guess.
If you dread something, you're kind of fearful about it.
I'll tell you one thing I always dread.
I dread going to the dentist.
I just hate it.
Most people do, except me.
I love going there.
I love the sound of the drill going into my tooth and all the stuff that flies up into the air when it's happening.
Well, in Taiwan, they put that cloth over your face, which is even worse for me.
So you dread something.
You dread tests, perhaps.
It's whatever you are fearful about coming that's around the corner.
You dread it.
Well, he dreads losing his reputation.
Your reputation is how other people think of you.
Whether it's true or not is another discussion, right?
You can have a good reputation and a bad reputation or no reputation at all.
But he has one.
He's pretty popular in school.
So even though he's drawn to her, he kind of wants to stay away because other kids are, you know, bullying her, which is a bad thing.
He's the student body president, so he's got his reputation to think about.
So he talks with her after school in the neighborhood there.
So, of course, no other students will be there and they won't notice him talking to her.
But he does avoid her in public, which means probably out in public, maybe at a store or something.
But I think this is referring to school here.
Yeah, I do, too.
In school, he probably doesn't talk to her at all or ignores her because he doesn't want people thinking,
hey, he talks to that weird girl.
Boy, that's really bad.
He shouldn't do that.
We should not elect him a student body president anymore.
So, yeah, he avoids her in public.
Still, his sincerity builds trust and a genuine friendship blossoms.
So she knows that he doesn't pay her attention in public, but she probably understands that.
But he has that sincerity of talking to her after school and that builds trust.
She starts to trust him and they have this genuine friendship.
It's a true friendship.
He's not just doing it.
He's not just becoming her friend because he feels sorry for her or she for him because she just likes him because he's a student body president.
They're actually genuine friends.
Yeah, when his friends mock Callie again, Jinsong erupts.
He punches them and ends up being suspended.
If you mock someone, you make fun of them in a cruel way.
Sometimes if you're just with your best friends and you mock each other, it's not cruel.
You're just kind of making fun of each other because you know each other's, I don't know, habits and the silly things we do.
You can mock your friends.
Here, it's not a nice mocking.
It's a mean mocking.
They're cruel to her.
And it makes him so angry, he erupts.
To suddenly become emotional or even violent, you can use this word to erupt.
Your temper can make you erupt and react in bad ways.
And he punches them, which can be pretty serious and get you into serious trouble.
And that's what happens to him.
He gets suspended.
If you're suspended from school, you're temporarily removed from attending school as a punishment.
And then Callie's world shifts without warning.
There's a big change in her life.
Her mother impulsively marries a new boyfriend and announces a move to Las Vegas, Nevada in the U.S.
Okay, so if you do something impulsively, you don't really think about it too much.
You just think, what the heck?
I'll just do that.
And you don't really stop and think, is that the right thing to do?
Yeah.
You just kind of do it without really thinking so much.
And they're going to move to Las Vegas, the gambling capital of the United States.
I guess people gamble all over the country now anyway.
But before she departs, Callie shares one last walk with Jin Sung, and he kisses her farewell.
So he knows she's going to leave.
She knows she's going to leave.
So they have one last walk together chatting about the future, and he gives her a kiss.
It's a farewell kiss to say goodbye.
It's been nice knowing you.
Then on the drive out to Las Vegas, Callie confronts her mother.
If you confront somebody or something, you face them, and you deal with some sort of problem
directly.
And she tells her mom, hey, I hate this constant moving.
It's causing me a lot of pain in my life.
She also talks to her mom about the advice her mother and doctor gave her about concealing
her Tourette's.
If you conceal something, guys, it simply means you're hiding something.
Well, you know, sometimes when you confront problems directly, you have great results.
And this is what happens.
Her mother apologizes.
Maybe her mother just was not seeing the situation clearly.
And once Callie talks to her directly, they begin communicating more openly, and that can only be a good thing.
So at her new school, Callie introduces herself honestly and discloses her Tourette syndrome.
She lets people know, I've got Tourette's.
I'm not going to hide it anymore.
I'm not going to conceal it.
I'm going to have these weird tics that you might want to make fun of me for, but I'm letting you know this.
I'm, you know, I'm accepting it, and I want you to accept it as well.
And surprisingly, her classmates respond with warmth and acceptance.
So I guess these classmates know a little bit about Tourette's, and therefore they think, we can't bully her.
She can't help it.
That's really stupid to do something like that.
Yeah.
And Callie and Jinsong stay in touch.
They write emails to each other and stuff like that.
And she's already planning a summer visit.
She's going to go back and visit Jinsong in the town she used to live in.
And hopefully this story will have a happy ending.
It sounds like it already did.
And that's it there.
That's all we have to talk about.
So let's take a listen or have a listen to our Chinese teacher now one last time.
再来我们看到第三段的第一个句子。
好,那受到同学的霸凌,不过还是有人对他比较友善的。
我们看到第一个句子这边就讲到唯一的例外呢就是静松。
好,那这是一个华裔的邻居。
那他在学校里也是备受瞩目。
怎么看到的?
请同学注意。
Prominent student body president.
好,所以这位静松哦,他是学生会的会长。
而且很出名。
Prominent就备受瞩目了。
那我们再看到第二个句子。
请同学呢注意文法结构。
这是一个分词构句。
那主词呢一样是静松。
静松 was drawn,抱歉,静松 is drawn to Kelly.
From the day she moves in.
好,那由于呢这边呢我们都是等于是小说说故事的时候,为了要让读者比较有这个清零现场,时态呢有些时候是会用现在式的。
那因为没有连接词,所以呢前面的he is drawn to,那我们就简化成了这个只留,只保留这个过去分词drawn to Kelly.
他其实是受到他吸引的。
好,然后呢这个静松,他很怕一件事。
Dreads losing his reputation.
Dread就是担心,害怕,忧虑什么事。
那后面呢加V-I-N-G.
那再来请同学看到的是第四个句子。
第四个句子最后面有一个blossoms。
这个blossom原本指的是开花,但是呢在文学里面呢我们常有这样的写法,就是用来形容抽象事物呢发展成熟。
那这两个人呢就发展出了友谊。
好,再来我们看到第四段。
那后来他们变成朋友,可是啊,Kelly的世界突然间呢,without warning,在没有任何预警的情况之下发生了转变,因为妈妈又要搬家了。
好,那我们看到第四个句子。
那车子开走了,他们要搬家了,on the drive,在路上的时候,Kelly confronts her mother,请同学看到confront这个字。
好,那这里所指的呢就是Kelly,她老实地跟她妈妈说出她心里面的感受。
她觉得很不舒服,怎么说?constant moving,因为不断地在搬家,而且呢,她妈妈还要她去隐瞒,跟别人隐瞒她的状况,concealing和condition。
这个conceal当然也是指希望尽量不要让别人发现她到底有哪些状况。
好,那我们看到呢,今天最后一个重点,在第五段的第一个句子,and,后面的这个动词,discloses。
这个句子就是,这个动词的意思就是揭露,Kelly呢,还是跟同学揭露她的病情了,她的状况。
好,以上就是我们针对这篇课文内容所说的中文讲解。see you next time.
All right, everybody, that brings us to the end of our lesson for today.
We summarized our featured work of literature for this edition of our magazine, Forget Me Not.
But in our next program, we're going to talk about the book in a little more depth.
So let's do that then.
But for now, everybody, we're going to say goodbye.
And we look forward to seeing you again next time.
From all of us here at English Digest, I'm Tom.
I'm Stephanie.
Goodbye.
Bye.